<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Arthur Dent</title>
    <link>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Arthur Dent</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 04:05:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Les Misérables by Victor Hugo</title>
      <link>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/les-mis%C3%A9rables-by-victor-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 04:05:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/les-mis%C3%A9rables-by-victor-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Although this detail has no connection whatever with the real substance of what we are about to relate, it will not be superfluous, if merely for the sake of exactness in all points, to mention here the various rumors and remarks which had been in circulation about him from the very moment when he arrived in the diocese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bool&#34;&gt;Bool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True or false, that which is said of men often occupies as important a place in their lives, and above all in their destinies, as that which they do. M. Myriel was the son of a councillor of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parliament_of_Aix-en-Provence&#34;&gt;Parliament of Aix&lt;/a&gt;; hence he belonged to the nobility of the bar. It was said that his father, destining him to be the heir of his own post, had married him at a very early age, eighteen or twenty, in accordance with a custom which is rather widely prevalent in parliamentary families. In spite of this marriage, however, it was said that Charles Myriel created a great deal of talk. He was well formed, though rather short in stature, elegant, graceful, intelligent; the whole of the first portion of his life had been devoted to the world and
to gallantry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The halls are nothing but rooms, and it is with difficulty that the air can be changed in them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conversation took place in the gallery dining-room on the ground-floor. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQw4w9WgXcQ&#34;&gt;Bishop&lt;/a&gt; remained silent for a moment; then he turned abruptly to the director of the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metamorphosis by Franz Kafka</title>
      <link>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/metamorphosis-by-franz-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 04:03:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/metamorphosis-by-franz-kafka/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-one&#34;&gt;Part One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning, when &lt;em&gt;Gregor Samsa&lt;/em&gt; woke from troubled dreams, he &lt;a href=&#34;./&#34;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; himself transformed in his bed into a horrible vermin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He lay on his armour-like back, and if he lifted his head a little he could see his brown belly, slightly domed and divided by arches into stiff sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bedding was hardly able to cover it and seemed ready to slide off any moment. His many legs, pitifully thin compared with the size of the rest of him, waved about helplessly as he looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-two&#34;&gt;Part Two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not until it was getting dark that evening that Gregor awoke from his deep and coma-like sleep. He would have woken soon afterwards anyway even if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t been disturbed, as he had had enough sleep and felt fully rested. But he had the impression that some hurried steps and the sound of the door leading into the front room being carefully shut had woken him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He pushed himself over to the door, feeling his way clumsily with his antennae - of which he was now beginning to learn the value - in order to see what had been happening there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole of his left side seemed like one, painfully stretched scar, and he limped badly on his two rows of legs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Street_light&#34;&gt;electric street lamps&lt;/a&gt; shone palely here and there onto the ceiling and tops of the furniture, but down below, where Gregor was, it was dark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use @ instead of HEAD</title>
      <link>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/use-at-instead-of-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 17:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ultinomics.github.io/ultinomics.org/blog/use-at-instead-of-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered that from git version &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/git/git/blob/master/Documentation/RelNotes/1.8.5.txt#L100&#34;&gt;1.8.5&lt;/a&gt; onwards, &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; can replace &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ git reset --hard @~2
$ git rebase -i @~10
$ git diff @~2..@~3
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also in most scenarios &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt; can be left out completely, so you can say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ git reset -- @{2}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ git reset -- HEAD@{2}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some getting used to, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely faster than typing &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>